In this video we introduce our Work-in-Progress paper about Squeezer,
a tool for designing juicy effects in game prototypes.
An example of adding juice to a game,
could be taking a simple breakout clone like this one,
and turning it into this:
The goal of juice is to make actions feel significant.
Juice is usually applied to provide feedback to the player
for any input and object interaction they perform,
as well as signalling when objects are created, destroyed or collected.
Designing juicy effects usually demands expertise within many subsystems,
and easily means working with several different subsystems at once.
Even using state of the art systems, it can be hard to know how to get going.
Squeezer is our attempt at simplifying that process,
by making it easy to add and design effect sequences for game prototypes.
Squeezer can also help designers by generating effect sequences for them,
based on a selected category and intensity.
Even allowing the designer to lock certain parts of the effect sequence,
while mutating or regenerating the rest.
The Squeezer workflow is slit into three steps,
(1) Setup Triggers,
(2) Generate or manually add sequences of effects to those triggers,
(3) Tweak or Mutate effects until they suit the game.
In the near future we will be expanding upon the generated effect sequences.
Use interactive evolution to help designers explore the possibility space
of effects within a game.
And looking at integrating the system within an automated game design process.
You can find Squeezer at github.com/pyjamads/Squeezer